<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Games | Moriah's Web]]></title>
  <link href="http://planetpony.com/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://planetpony.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-21T11:46:02-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://planetpony.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Moriah Trostler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rock Band Mod Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://planetpony.com/blog/2008/10/03/rock-band-mod-update/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://planetpony.com/blog/2008/10/03/rock-band-mod-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>10-3-08</h2>

<p>Just a quick update. I recently changed up my drum set a bit. I got myself a used Roland PD-120 to be my snare and a PD-80 for the high hat. I though the mesh pads would be even quieter and enhance my Rock Band experience. They really are not much quieter but the sound is different then the rubber thud. They actually kind of sound like a real drum that is just very muted. Another reason for getting the PD-120 was because it is bigger and I can use a snare stand with it. Since adding the double bass pedal my left knee would hit on the bar the Yamaha had for holding the snare. Now with snare on the stand that problem is gone.</p>

<p>I tried to make a video since that seems to be thing to do. It turned out pretty boring but if you are interested be my guest:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/I7sru_YQpeg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>One neat thing I discovered was using practice mode to play the full song but play the sound of the drums out the actual drum brain. It really surprised me how forgiving Rock Band is with your timing. Once you actually listen to yourself playing you can hear how off you can be and still have Rock Band trigger a hit. I really recommend if you have speakers hooked up to your drum brain trying practice mode. It is a cool way to get drumless tracks to play along with and improve your drum skills.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rock Band Uber Mod!]]></title>
    <link href="http://planetpony.com/blog/2008/05/05/rock-band-uber-mod-/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://planetpony.com/blog/2008/05/05/rock-band-uber-mod-</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After completing my pedal mod I kept reading about what other improvements could be made.  I ended up deciding that a full blown electronic drum kit was required. After much deliberation I talked myself into dropping $700 on a Yamaha DTXplorer.  Thanks to Flash for distilling 100+ pages of a <a href="http://www.rockband.com/forums/showthread.php?t=20420&amp;amp;page=102">forum</a> thread into <a href="http://theflashspeaks.wordpress.com/2008/02/03/playing-rock-band-with-a-yamaha-dtxplorer-how-to/">this</a> site I was able to complete the mod.</p>

<p>Instead of soldering to the almost invisible points on the back of the RB circuit board I soldered directly to the button pads.  Being careful to keep the wires as far to the outside and a flat as possible kept the buttons working like usual.  I also used the USB power to run the MSA to avoid having another power brick.</p>

<p>I think the controller box turned out pretty well.  Playing on the real
drum pads made a huge difference in response.  The base pedal being
piezo instead of a reed relay makes it require much less movement to
trigger.  I have been trying to play the songs using the proper cymbals
and toms with required me to go back to medium difficulty for a couple
of days.  I am back to doing mostly hard now with a couple of songs
completed on expert.  Overall it has been a very cool experience.  It
is my first major hack and now that it is done I have to find something else
to hack!</p>

<p></p>

<p><a href="/images/orig/rb_yahama_2.jpg"><img src="/images/small/rb_yahama_2.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Rb_yahama_2" ></a></p>

<p><a href="/images/orig/rb_blackbox.jpg"><img src="/images/small/rb_blackbox.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Rb_blackbox" ></a></p>

<h2>UPDATE - 5/22/05</h2>

<p>Now that it has been a few week my skills are to back to where they were from before the hack.  Playing on a real set is so much better.  I really like that I have the ability to use the right pad for the right sound.  I saw that Guitar Hero is going to have cymbals and I think Rock Band should have done that to start with.  I wish I could say I was rocking on expert all the time but I just cant get my kick speed up.  I might just have to add a double bass pedal.</p>

<p>I finally decided to open the box and post pictures.<br />
<a href="/images/orig/pict2284_2.jpg"><img src="/images/small/pict2284_2.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Pict2284" ></a></p>

<p>I bought the MSA disassembled.  That was a lot of soldering!</p>

<p><a href="/images/orig/pict2281.jpg"><img src="/images/small/pict2281.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Pict2281" ></a></p>

<p>I could not get the wire to stick to the points that Flash listed on his site so I decided to use the buttons.  The buttons still work and I can use the drum pads for navigation.<br /></p>

<p><a href="/images/orig/pict2283.jpg"><img src="/images/small/pict2283.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Pict2283" ></a></p>

<p>I used the usb power to run the MSA.  The red is positive and the black is ground.</p>

<p><a href="/images/orig/pict2287.jpg"><img src="/images/small/pict2287.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Pict2287" ></a></p>

<p>I dremeled the original Rock Band drum controller down and then epoxied into the project box.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rock Band Bass Pedal Hacked]]></title>
    <link href="http://planetpony.com/blog/2008/02/05/rock-band-bass-pedal-hacked/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://planetpony.com/blog/2008/02/05/rock-band-bass-pedal-hacked</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The bass pedal that comes with Rock Band is not the nicest piece of hardware. This weekend I finished a mod I found on <a href="http://rockband.scorehero.com/forum/viewforum.php?f=1038&amp;amp;sid=635a98f3a42f22be54ac8fe68807cffe">rockband.scorehero.com</a> to replace the pedal with a real bass drum pedal. I used a reed relay and magnets from Radio Shack to get the Pearl pedal connected. What an amazing difference! No more leg fatigue and much faster response. I urge anyone who really enjoys drumming on Rock Band to make the change.</p>

<p>I am still in the process of building a switch that will allow me to use both the new pedal and the original at the same time. The schematic <a href="http://rockband.scorehero.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=3428&amp;amp;postdays=0&amp;amp;postorder=asc&amp;amp;start=15">here</a> is what I am using. I just need to get it off the breadboard and permanently soldered.</p>

<p><img src="/images/orig/p2051660.jpg" width="800" height="1066" title="p2051660" >]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
